Seedence 2.5 is finally here, it brings some massive jump in motion realism, 30 seconds generations and up to 50 references.
Today, we're mastering character and environment consistency so a video will look like one complete story.
I'll walk you through a step by step workflow to fix any broken scene, and I'm giving away my exact prompt templates for free and the cloth skill.
Let's get into it.
We will have a total of 4 steps and I'll show them to you one by one.
We can start with the first step, which is building consistent reference sheets.
We're starting inside the cloud and there are 2 ways to craft these.
The first way is to simply copy the templates and attach your base images.
The second way is to use a custom cloth skill, so let's start with the first method.
Find the character templates in the provided document, copy it, go back into the cloud and paste the prompt.
Click to add files and upload your character base image.
At the very end of the prompt, it instructs the AI to fill the prompt using the attached character image.
And then press send the prompt.
Now, I'll open a second window and do the exact same thing for the environment.
Go back into the document and find the exterior environment template.
Copy the template, go back into the cloud and paste it.
At the very end, it's saying, fill in this prompt using the attached image.
Attach your environment base image alongside with the prompt and send it.
Now, copy the new character prompt that the clothes are generated.
Open JGBT and click create an image.
Paste the prompt you just copied and the most important part here is to actually attach your base image of the character alongside with the text.
At the very end of the prompt, I will add an extraction for a 16 by 9 aspect ratio and just click generate.
We have to do the exact same thing for our environment.
Go back and copy the generated environment prompt from the cloud, paste into JGBT and add your environment base image.
Write in 16 by 9 aspect creation instruction at the very end and send the prompt.
As you can see, our environment and our character reference sheets has been successfully generated.
This is the exact same process for all your subjects, whether they are vehicles, environments, characters or props,
the workflow is exactly the same for all those.
Now, I'll show you a second method.
The second way to craft this consistent character sheets is by using CloudSkill.
I made my own CloudSkill to speed up this process, which will link in the description below.
Alongside with the document containing templates, click the plus icon and upload all of your reference images at once.
I have two exterior environments and one character uploaded.
Click plus, go to your skills and select concept sheet builder skill and press generate.
The skill will automatically analyze all the references and depending on what each one is, it uses the matching template.
As you can see, it created one exterior template based on the first image, which is labeled E1.
If we scroll down, we can see the second exterior template, which matches image E2.
If we scroll down further, we can see the character template.
From here, it is the exact same process.
You just copy these prompts into tragedyBT, click create an image and attach the base images.
You will get the exact same output as the previous manual way.
The skill is just here to speed your process up.
If you do not want the CloudSkills, the manual method works just as well and provides completely identical results.
One more important thing for when you save your reference images.
When you don't want an image, like this seller, make sure to name the actual file clearly.
Save it as seller or give the character a specific name.
This makes it much easier to work with later.
It keeps your taking consistent route the entire workflow and simplifies everything later.
Make sure to name every character with a proper title.
If you have multiple environments, named in specifically like Stoll or Street,
this will make the entire process much simpler later on.
And that covers the first step.
And now, we are moving over to step 2, which is writing a story and generating CDN 2.5 videos.
The first thing we need to do inside the Cloud is write a short story.
And roughly describe what we want to make using the reference images we have.
As you can see here, I already prepared a full prompt and story.
I wrote in the very top of a plot that reference images and here is a story for CDN 2.5 video generator.
And now, we will pull the references.
After the story, I instructed Cloud 2.
Use this template to craft a single, complete 32nd CDN 2.5 prompt.
The generator is one clip.
Tag references exactly as uploaded files are named.
Example, Simon.
Never generic place orders like image 1.
Use the exact names everywhere RF appears.
As you can see, I specified using the exact names.
If I click on the seller here, it is named seller.
If I click on the character, his name Simon.
This one is named revolver.
It is set up like that for everything to make the process simpler.
Here is a CDN video prompt template.
And now, we will generate a story.
Just press generate.
This is the first video prompt we received.
You do not have to accept the first result in returns, obviously.
You can iterate, go where each shot and choose what you want to keep or change.
Once the process is done, copy the video prompt and head over to Dramina.
Paste the video in the text box.
Select CDN 2.5, choose Omni reference and adjust the time setting to 30 seconds.
Now, upload all of your images.
I have uploaded all of my images here.
Next, we need to tag all the references.
Scroll down the prompt and tag everything.
As you can see, we tag Simon, add Simon, seller and go down the prompt tagging every reference.
One that is done, press generate.
I already generated the first clip, so now I'll show you the next step.
Now that we did that, we generated our first video.
And spot all the things that went from in the video.
For example, as you can see here, the seller is not standing at a stall.
If we move further along, the background here is still not standing at a stall.
What we need to do for those shots is take the prompt, go back into cloth
and specify the changes.
For example, write, short 3, seller should be the stall, or copy a specific section,
like a close-up shot and change the detail you want to adjust.
Specify the timestamps, like short 6 to 8 seconds or short 10 to 12 seconds
and prompt cloth to rewrite those parts.
Once you do that, cloth will write a new prompt.
Copy the new prompt, go back into Dramina and generate again.
As you can see, I did just that.
First, I took my original video.
Then I generated a second one to try and redo the shots.
Then I generated a third one.
I ran this exact process three times, reiterating every student went from.
However, you notice that some details just not happened, even if you split the prompt for them.
For example, at some points, getting the seller to stand at a stall
just did not happen in the way I wanted because they hallucinated.
I will show you how to fix that in the next step.
Once you have your three video variations, check them one last time
for instance that you like, but it is missing a detail or did not turn as planned.
I will show you how to fix those specific scenes in step three.
Moving on to the next step, which is fixing a broken scene.
The way to do this is actually pretty simple.
For this video here, the seller ended up missing from the shot.
And it's fine, because I'll show you how to fix it right now.
He is actually missing from two shots.
The first shot, and here at the 7th mark, we're going to fix the second one.
And I'm going to show you how.
This is the exact same process for two, so this scene was good,
but it was missing a character to stall.
I will take the whole 30 second video here and download it.
Then I will open my Aitor.
I use Adobe Premiere Pro for this.
But any other Aitor works for this trick as well.
I will cut five seconds containing two shots.
One where the seller is clearly visible.
And another shot we need to fix.
We're going to do that now.
We will not cut the first shot from here.
I'm going to cut where the seller appears.
Then cut where the second shot ends.
Press I and O on your keyboard to set your in and out points.
Select these five seconds and export them.
Then, upload a five second clip back into Dramina.
When you do that, write your prompt.
Keep the video at video one.
Exactly as it is in shot two.
Only add at seller.
The man already seen in shot one.
Standing behind a stall counter working.
Turning his head left and right.
Change nothing.
I uploaded my video and the seller reference image.
And now let's see the video.
As you can see, it worked pretty well.
It added a seller who was missing.
And now this video is a usable shot.
Why they cut five seconds instead of two or three seconds?
Because this gives CDN 2.5 more data
on how the character looks in the environment
when he is standing at a shot.
Appalling the seller reference makes it easier
for the AI to map him out.
Depending on what you're trying to fix,
you can use less or more than five seconds.
It simply comes down to what you're fixing.
And now that we know how to fix a scene
and you have all our scenes and videos ready,
we can move on to the next and final step.
Step four, which is choosing the right shots and editing.
What we have to do now is know the video
that we fixed in step three,
along with the first three original videos we generated.
Then we'll go into the editor.
This is the video that I already ate it.
So how do you choose all the shots?
I took all the videos,
video one, video two, and video three.
And the fixed one from step three.
I went over each video.
I looked at every shot to see what I like
and what I didn't like.
For example, I didn't like this shot as much.
It is the same for the video two.
This shot was okay, but it was missing the seller in the stall.
Instead of fixing that,
I choose the shots from the video three
because it's more cinematic,
the first shot I'm talking about.
I like it way better.
So I did not even bother fixing the other one
for a second shot.
I like this one.
I'm going to fix the scene.
So I use this third scene for the shot three.
I went over each shot and choose the shots that I like
and discarded the one that I didn't like.
Because all of these have the same environment,
the same character and the same subjects,
they use the same reference throughout.
So it's pretty consistent.
And as you can see here,
I choose the first shots from the video three.
Then for a second shot,
I use the video two.
Then this is the scene we fixed from a step three.
As you can see,
now there is a person standing at the stall.
After that, it goes back to video two.
Then changes to video three.
What they did here is either an effect
like a fade out sound effect.
So it can blend the sound between the two.
I like the video three all the way to the end.
When I put these shots on top of each other,
I try to blend the sounds
so it can sound better and more natural when the video is played.
In the very end, as you can see here, there is music.
How did I generate this music?
After generating all the scenes,
I simply ask Lord,
what music would feed this 30-second short film?
And I generated that music with elaborate music too.
You can also generate using Google Lira 3 or sooner.
It doesn't matter.
You can simply prompt for that and ask Lord to do it.
After I chose the sequence,
I sported it with music
and the final version is ready.
Now, let's see the final result with sound.
That's how you make a complete story in four steps.
And the final version is ready.
Thank you for watching.
If you like this video, consider subscribing
and I'll see you in the next one.